iabtechlab.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy - IAB Tech Lab

**This Privacy Policy was last modified in July 2018.  
**

This is our official Privacy Policy which forms part of your legal agreement with us UNDER OUR [TERMS OF USE](https://iabtechlab.com/index.php/terms-of-use/). Please read our Privacy Policy carefully to be sure you understand how we collect and use information and under what circumstances we share information.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify, add or delete provisions of this Privacy Policy at any time.  We will post the effective date of any change at the top of this Privacy Policy. Your use of our Digital Property after the effective date of any such modification means you accept and agree to be bound by the Privacy Policy, as modified. We urge you to come back to this digital page and review this Privacy Policy regularly so that you remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply to you.

**COLLECTING PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
“Personal Information” may include information such as your name, postal address, email, and telephone number. You voluntarily provide this information to us, for example, when you register with our Digital Property or make a request for information or services.  We may use this information for purposes including responding to your requests as well as to provide you access to interactive features ( _i.e._ , conferences or webinars). _See_ the section entitled “How We Use Information” for more detail. We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to others except as otherwise disclosed in this policy. If necessary, our Digital Property may collect payment and payment instrument information from you for the purpose of billing you for products, services, or event tickets you purchase through our Digital Property. If you elect to use our “Refer-A-Member” service in order to tell someone else about us, we will ask you to provide your email address and the email address of the individual you wish to inform. We will use this information to send a one-time automated email inviting them to visit our Digital Property and indicating the invitation arose from your suggestion.

**COLLECTING NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
We use third party operational service providers ( _see_ “Information Sharing” below) and technology that can collect and transmit information that is associated with computers and devices that visit our Digital Properties.  Data gathered via these technologies do not personally identify you. Although the term “cookie” commonly is used to refer to a small text file stored on a computer that can log visits to web sites and/or can contain log-in information so you don’t have to re-enter information each time you visit, we will use the term “cookie” to refer generically to any technology that can collect or transmit information about visits to our Digital Properties. “Cookie” information typically includes such data as the referral web domain, the type of operating system and browser you are using, mobile device identifiers, the date and time of your visit, location data, information relating to activities on our Digital Properties ( _e.g._ , “clickstream” data) and other technical attributes of visits to our Digital Properties. We use the information collected through cookies to analyze trends, administer our Websites, track movements on our Website or applications Digital Properties and gather aggregate demographic information about visitors so we can continually improve our Digital Properties. Cookies store information that allows our Digital Property to recognize a user’s computer or access device each time it is used to visit our Digital Property and cookies can keep count of how often you return to our Digital Property. Cookies can also track how you use our Digital Property, your preferences for features and functions, and can store information such as your log-in information, so you don’t have to re-enter them each time you return to our Digital Property. We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer or device for purposes that are unrelated to our Digital Property or your interaction with our Digital Property. You may stop or restrict cookies on your computer or purge them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences and you should consult the operating instructions that apply to your browser for instructions should you wish to do so and in general to determine how best to configure your browser settings to meet your requirements. Note that if you “turn off,” purge, or disable cookies, although you may still use our Digital Property, you may not be able to use all of the features, functions, or services available on our Digital Property.

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION**  
We will use information we collect or obtain when you use our Digital Properties as described in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise disclosed at the time of collection, to:

  * Conduct internal research;
  * Operate and administer our Digital Properties;
  * Ensure compliance with our [Terms of Use](https://iabtechlab.com/index.php/terms-of-use/);
  * Respond to your requests for products, services, and/or information;
  * Communicate with you about IAB Technology Laboratory products, services, events, promotions, and other items we believe will be of interest to you;
  * Fulfill your purchases or registrations; and
  * Provide member services including publishing a directory for members.

**ADVERTISERS, CO-SPONSORS, AND LINKS TO OTHERS**  
Our Digital Property may contain or display information from sponsors, co-sponsors, advertisers, operational service providers, or others that offer to make information, products, and/or services available, and/or that provide opportunities to participate in promotions or engage in activities or that link or redirect your browser to other websites, web pages, materials, or organizations. We may also use third parties for the purpose of administering, operating, configuring our Digital Property, maintaining and providing internal support for our Digital Property and Content on our Digital Property, to display and serve advertising, for distributing our online, email, messaged, or web-based newsletters and other information. We will refer to these third parties as our “operational service providers.” Even if we have a relationship with a third party you may encounter or see on our Digital Property, the advertising, links or references to third parties or any of their websites, including any cookies or other technology they may use, are not under our control and they have their own terms, conditions, policies, and practices that apply to you in connection with their websites, including those concerning collection, use and disclosure of your information (including Personal Information). Some IAB Technology Laboratory services, such as seminars, educational events, conferences, newsletters, and discussion groups, may be co-sponsored in conjunction with other companies that are not under the control of the IAB Technology Laboratory. Whenever we are involved in the provision of such services, we will disclose the name of our co-sponsor. Co-sponsors of these IAB Technology Laboratory services are not under our control and when you participate, register, or engage in other online activities related to these co-sponsored IAB Technology Laboratory Services, you should be aware that you are providing your information, which may include Personal Information, to us and the co-sponsor, and that their policies, practices, terms and conditions, and not ours, apply to their collection and use of your information. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Digital Property or take advantage of advertised offers, links or other references, many of which may direct you or your Internet browser to websites or web pages of another party. You should read their privacy statements and the terms and conditions that apply because we are not responsible for any of the terms or conditions, privacy practices, the content, functions, features, activities, and/or transactions you may engage in when you are not using our Digital Properties. If we use an operational service provider to serve advertising to you on our Digital Property or elsewhere on the Internet, the operational service provider may use information about your visits to our Digital Properties, or other websites around the Internet, in order to serve advertisements about products and services that may be of interest to you. This type of advertising is known as interest-based advertising.  In the course of serving interest-based ads, our operational service provider may use cookies and other technologies. IAB Technology Laboratory is a founding member of the Digital Advertising Alliance, and if you would like more information about interest-based advertising, and to know your choices about not having this information used by the operational service providers that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance, please click here: [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

**INFORMATION SHARING**  
We may share Personal Information with our operational service providers to assist us in connection with our Digital Properties, or other services we provide, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. We also currently use an operational service provider to measure our Digital Property traffic and it may also collect information (but not Personal Information) about your use of our Digital Properties to help us improve our Digital Properties. If you would like more information about how the operational service provider we use for this service collect and use this information, please visit: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245> and <http://webtrends.com/terms-policies/privacy/privacy-notice>. We also reserve the right to share Personal Information:

  * When compelled by a governmental agency, law, regulation, a court or other legal process;
  * If we believe you are, have or may violate any law, regulation or our [Terms of Use](https://iabtechlab.com/terms-of-use/);
  * If we believe you are or may be a threat to safety, security, property, interests or rights of us or anyone else;
  * In order to investigate, respond to or resolve problems or inquiries or protect, enforce or defend our rights, assets and/or interests; and
  * In a merger, acquisition, change of control, partial or total sale or transfer of assets including in a bankruptcy proceeding, joint venture, or other business combination.

**OPTING OUT**  
If you register on or with our Digital Properties, you are agreeing and consenting to receive information and updates about your use of our Digital Properties or our Services for which you register. You may opt out of receiving marketing email communications from us by completing this [form](http://www.iab.com/unsubscribe) or by following the unsubscribe instructions we will include in each email we send you. _See_ the section above on “Advertisers, Co-Sponsors, and Links to Others” for more details on your choices with operational service providers.

**SECURITY**  
As you may appreciate, the Internet is a public network and we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the IAB Technology Laboratory or others to, through, or from our Digital Property, will be free from unauthorized access or interference by third parties. By using our Digital Property, you are agreeing to assume this risk and any and all responsibility and liability that may arise. We have put in place reasonable procedures to help safeguard information and we limit access to your Personal Information to only those employees who need access in order to perform their duties.

**UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU**  
We will provide you with a mechanism to allow and enable you to correct or update the Personal Information in our current records that we have obtained from you. You can review and change your Personal Information by contacting us by email at [support@iabtechlab.com](mailto:support@iabtechlab.com) or by telephone at 212.380.4728. Certain Personal Information may not be changed without authentication and you may be asked to provide additional information to allow us to verify your identity in order to change those. If you ask us to remove your Personal Information, we reserve the right to retain as much of your Personal Information and for so long as necessary to comply with our legal, regulatory, internal audit, and record-keeping requirements.

**CONTACT US**  
For questions relating to privacy, we can be contacted at: [support@iabtechlab.com](mailto:support@iabtechlab.com) or 212.380.4728 or by mail, proper postage prepaid, at Interactive Advertising Bureau, Inc., 116 E. 27th Street, New York, New York, 10016, Attention: Privacy Administrator.
